Ruijie Meng

Ph.D. Candidate, School of Computing, National University of Singapore (NUS)

Email: ruijie@comp.nus.edu.sg Address: COM3-02-20, 11 Research Link, Singapore 119391

Mobile: (+65) 89498841 Academic Homepage: https://mengrj.github.io/

BIOGRAPHY

Ruijie Meng is currently a Ph.D. candidate at National University of Singapore, advised by Provost's Chair Professor Abhik Roychoudhury. Her research focuses on improving important software systems, in particular, the reliability and security aspects of concurrent, stateful and reactive software systems (e.g., distributed systems and network protocols). Her research interests span software engineering and security topics: fuzz testing, software model checking, program analysis and LLMs for testing. Her research work has led to several papers published at premier conferences in both the software engineering domain (e.g., ICSE, FSE, and ASE) and the security domain (e.g., CCS and NDSS). She has developed several open-source automated security testing tools that are responsible for many previously-unknown (critical) vulnerabilities discovered in large real-world software systems.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. candidate, National University of Singapore (NUS), Singapore

Aug 2020 - Present

Major: Computer Science, School of Computing

• Advisor: Abhik Roychoudhury

• GPA: 4.83/5

M.Eng., University of Chinese Academy of Sciences (UCAS), Beijing, China

Sep 2017 - Jun 2020

• State Key Laboratory of Computer Science, Institute of Software Chinese Academy of Sciences

• Advisor: Yan Cai

• GPA: 3.81/4 (Rank: 1/102)

B.Eng., Tianjin University (TJU), Tianjin, China

Sep 2013 - Jun 2017

• Major: Software Engineering, School of Computer Software

• GPA: 3.75/4 (Rank: 3/113)

B.Ec., Nankai University (NKU), Tianjin, China

Sep 2014 - Jun 2017

• Minor: Finance, School of Finance

RESEARCH PROJECTS

My recent research projects have been focused on developing innovative fuzzing algorithms to test **stateful and reactive software systems**. Specifically, my projects are over three main dimensions:

- Advancing Fuzzing for More Complex Test Oracles: Existing fuzzing cannot check property violations. We leverage the concept of automat-theoretic model checking to direct fuzzing to search for LTL-property violations.
- Navigating Fuzzing towards Deep States: Existing code feedback is not effective in guiding fuzzing towards deep states of reactive systems. We leverage LLMs to reason protocol states in fuzzing network protocols and build the first greybox fuzzer for distributed systems guided by model behaviors.
- Capturing Effect of Complex Program Environment: As reactive systems interact with complex execution environments, we propose fuzz testing to capture effect of different environments, avoiding environment modelling. Beyond these, I also worked on detection of concurrency bugs and vulnerabilities via program analysis.

PUBLICATIONS

• Program Environment Fuzzing arXiv'24 Ruijie Meng, Gregory J. Duck, Abhik Roychoudhury arXiv preprint arXiv:2404.13951 Large Language Model guided Protocol Fuzzing NDSS'24 Ruijie Meng, Martin Mirchev, Marcel Böhme, Abhik Roychoudhury Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS), 2024. Greybox Fuzzing of Distributed Systems CCS'23 Ruijie Meng, George Pirlea, Abhik Roychoudhury, Ilya Sergey ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS), 2023. • Linear-time Temporal Logic guided Greybox Fuzzing ICSE'22 Ruijie Meng, Zhen Dong, Jialin Li, Ivan Beschastnikh, Abhik Roychoudhury IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE), 2022. • Low-Overhead Deadlock Prediction ICSE'20 Yan Cai, **Ruijie Meng**, Jens Palsberg IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE), 2020. ConVul: An Effective Tool for Detecting Concurrency Vulnerabilities ASE'19 Ruijie Meng, Biyun Zhu, Hao Yun, Haicheng Li, Yan Cai, Zijiang Yang IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering Tool (ASE), 2019. • Detecting Concurrency Memory Corruption Vulnerabilities ESEC/FSE'19 Yan Cai, Biyun Zhu, Ruijie Meng, Hao Yun, Liang He, Purui Su, Bin Liang ACM European Software Engineering Conference/Symposium on the Foundations of Software Engineering (ESEC/FSE), 2019. ConRS: A Requests Scheduling Framework for Increasing Concurrency Degree of COMPSAC'19 Server Programs Biyun Zhu, Ruijie Meng, Zhenyu Zhang, W.K.Chan IEEE International Computer Software and Applications Conference (COMPSAC), 2019. **SECURITY FINDINGS** severity level, 7 CVEs are classified as CRITICAL, and 13 CVEs are categorized as HIGH:

Our tools have uncovered several zero-day security-critical vulnerabilities and granted with CVEs. In CVSS

• CVE-2023-37117	• CVE-2023-51713	• CVE-2023-31654	• CVE-2023-31655	• CVE-2023-3138
• CVE-2023-30635	• CVE-2023-30636	• CVE-2023-30637	• CVE-2021-38386	• CVE-2021-38387
• CVE-2021-42141	• CVE-2021-42142	• CVE-2021-42143	• CVE-2021-42144	• CVE-2021-42145
• CVE-2021-42146	• CVE-2021-42147	• CVE-2021-38311	• CVE-2021-40523	• CVE-2021-40524

ACADEMIC SERVICES

- Program Committee for ASE 2024 Tool Demonstration Track, 2024
- Reviewer for the Journal of Systems & Software (JSS), 2024
- Program Committee for ISSTA 2024 Artifact Evaluation, 2024
- Reviewer for IEEE Transactions on Computer-Aided Design of Integrated Circuits and Systems (TCAD), 2023
- Reviewer for ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM), 2023
- Program Committee for ISSTA 2023 Artifact Evaluation, 2023
- Program Committee for FUZZING 2022 Workshop@NDSS Artifact Evaluation, 2022
- Program Committee for ISSTA 2022 Artifact Evaluation, 2022
- Program Committee for ICSE 2022 Artifact Evaluation, 2022
- Student Volunteer for ESEC/FSE 2022, 2022

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Fuzzing Summer School Lecturer	National University of Singapore May 2024
CS5219 Automated Software Validation Teaching assistant	National University of Singapore Aug 2023 – Dec 2023
CS2040 Data Structures and Algorithms Teaching assistant	National University of Singapore Jan 2023 – Apr 2023
CS5219 Automated Software Validation Teaching assistant	National University of Singapore Aug 2022 – Dec 2022
CS2040 Data Structures and Algorithms Teaching assistant	National University of Singapore Jan 2022 – Apr 2022
CS2040S Data Structures and Algorithms Teaching assistant	National University of Singapore Aug 2021 – Dec 2021

SELECTED AWARDS

NUS Dean's Graduate Research Excellence Award	2023
NUSGS Research Incentive Award	2023 - 2024
NUS Teaching Fellowship Nomination	2023
NUS SoC Research Achievement Award	2023
• Singapore President's Graduate Fellowship	2020 - 2024
• Outstanding Graduate of Beijing (Top 2%)	2020
• Outstanding Graduate of University of Chinese Academy of Sciences (Top 2%)	2020
• President's Fellowship of University of Chinese Academy of Sciences (Top 2%)	2020

• China National Scholarship (<i>Top 2%</i>)	2019
ACM SIGAI Scholarship	2019
ACM SIGSOFT CAPS fund	2019
• First Prize Scholarship of University of Chinese Academy of Sciences (Top 10%)	2018, 2019
 Outstanding Bachelor Thesis of Tianjin University (Top 10%) 	2017
Outstanding Graduate of Tianjin University (Top 10%)	2017